■
双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译     唐朝栗子
翻译    托曼
翻译    泰温公爵
君临 King's Landing
红堡
Red Keep
翻译    麻绳力攻
赫伦堡 Harrenhal
校对    xiadamaozi
校对    suerhine
派
Pyke
克
城
派
Pyke
克
城
复校   守誓剑
bran的夏天
复校    Violet_rosa
临冬城 Winterfell
精校   CCXX
监制    旧镇老翁
后期   加文・维斯特林  poplar
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)
绝境长城 the Wall
衣柜军团力作《权力的游戏：漫画小说》实体书即将发售
最新进度请关注新浪微博@指文图书        敬请期待！
颤抖海 Shivering Sea
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治・R・R・马丁
魁尔斯Qarth
权力的游戏
第二季 第九集
衣柜字幕组
第九集  “黑水大战”
"Blackwater"
就这样
That's it
戴佛斯・席渥斯
洋葱骑士
史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩
狭海中的王
马索斯・席渥斯
戴佛斯・席渥斯之子
潮汐对我们不利
The tide's against us
是 但风向对我们有利
Aye, but we have the wind
足以送我们直抵城门
She'll blow us straight to the gate.
你要回家了
You're coming home.
我离开君临这家已有20年之久
King's Landing hasn't been home for 20 years.
大半辈子都在跟王家舰队躲迷藏
I spent most of my life dodging the Royal Fleet.
现在却要与他们正面交锋
And now I'm sailing right at them.
我们就是王家舰队
This is the Royal Fleet.
你也不再是走私者了 你是王家舰队总司令
And you're not a smuggler anymore, you're the high captain.
现在的王家舰队可不止一个
Of course there are several Royal Fleets at the moment.
过了今晚就不是了 当太阳升起之后
Not after tonight. When the sun rises,
史坦尼斯会坐上铁王座
Stannis will sit on the Iron Throne
你会当上首相
and you will be his Hand.
- 诸神保佑  - 只有一个神
- Gods be good. - God.
父亲 一个真神 他看顾着我们
Father, there is only one and he watches over us.
- 但不看顾他们？ - 他看顾着所有人
- But not over them? - Over all of us.
君临的百姓不会支持伪王
The people of King's Landing did not choose the false King
乔佛里・拜拉席恩
Joffrey Baratheon.
他们很乐意看到他的头被插在枪上
They will be glad to see his head on a spike.
不管怎么说 我们得先把他的头砍下来才行
Well, first we have to put it there.
我们的船是他们的十倍
Our ships outnumber theirs 10 to one.
我们的人马是他们的五倍
Our army outnumber theirs five to one.
君临城从没被攻破过
Those walls have never been breached.
而守城的那些人
And the men guarding the walls,
可不会把你当解放者
when they see you, they don't see a liberator.
在他们眼中  你是想要烧毁他们城市的陌生人
They see a stranger come to set their city on fire.
我相信光之王
I have faith in the Lord of Light.
相信我们的事业
I have faith in our cause.
相信司令大人你
And I have faith in my captain.
提利昂・兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 代理首相
雪伊
珊莎的侍女
害怕吗 我的狮子？
Are you afraid, my lion?
如果君临城破 史坦尼斯会烧死城内每一个兰尼斯特
If the city falls, Stannis will burn every Lannister he can find.
我当然害怕
Of course I'm afraid.
我不会让他们伤害你的
I won't let them hurt you.
我是兰尼斯特家的人
I'm a Lannister.
没法选择自己的命运
I don't have a choice in all this.
但这场战争与你无关
But it's not your war.
现在与我有关了
It is now.
不是万事都能靠你的身子解决的
You can't fuck your way out of everything.
但到目前为止都很顺利
I have so far.
还记得初次见面时 你在帐篷里对我说的话吗？
Do you remember what you said when you met me in your tent?
你要我拿出世界末日的劲头
That I should make love to you like it was your
跟你做爱
last day on this earth.
瑟曦・兰尼斯特
摄政太后
如你所知 陛下
As you know, Your Grace,
学士对他所效力的家族的责任
it is not only the sworn duty of a Maester
派席尔
首席学士
不止是执行主人的命令
to carry out the wishes of the house he serves,
更要在战争时期
but also to offer guidance
为主人提供必要的指导和建议
and counsel in times of war.
你的谏言一直都明智而慎重
Your words are always wise and measured.
- 如果你可以……  - 如果有什么不同的话
- If you could... - If anything,
那就是学士的责任
a Maester's duties become more urgent
在战争和骚乱中变得更加重要
in times of war and turmoil.
我记得在先王……
I remember back in the days of king...
你给我带了东西来？
You brought me something?
是的
Yes.
夜影之水
Essence of Nightshade
极其有效也非常危险
is as dangerous as it is efficacious.
在红酒中加入一滴
A single drop in a cup of wine
就能缓和紧绷的神经
suffices to soothe ragged nerves.
三滴会带来
Three drops will bring on a deep
无梦的深眠
and dreamless sleep.
十滴的话...
ten drops, however...
我知道十滴的后果
I know what 10 drops will bring.
- 陛下 可否容我冒昧地问... - 不可
- Your Grace, if I may ask... - You may not.
你一定有很多事要忙
You must have a lot of work to do.
众多勇士很快就会需要你的谏言了
I'm sure many brave men will need your wisdom soon.
是的 围城往往...
Yes. A siege is very...
注意楼梯台阶 大学士 对你来说太多了
Be careful on the stairs, Grand Maester. There are so many.
陛下
Your Grace.
噢 他这样说
and so he spoke
卡斯特梅的爵爷他这样说
that Lord of Castamere
然而今天 每逢雨季
but now the rains
雨水在大厅哭泣
weep o'er his halls
波隆
都城守备队队长
内里却无人影
with no one there to hear
然而今天 每逢雨季
yes, now the rains
雨水在大厅哭泣
weep o'er his halls
内里却无魂灵
and not a soul to hear.
- 敬大伙！   - 兰尼斯特万岁！
- To the boys! - Lannisters!
你从哪学到这首兰尼斯特的歌？
Where'd you learn the Lannister song?
喝醉的兰尼斯特呗
Drunk Lannisters.
你的嗓子真不赖
You've got a pretty voice.
承蒙夸奖
Thank you very much.
我也喜欢你的鼻子
And I like your nose.
你的鼻子被打破过多少次？
How many times you break it?
哦 让我想想
Well, now let's see.
第一次我才五岁
First time I was five.
我老妈用拨火棍给了我一下子
Me mom smacked me with an iron poker.
哦--
Ooh.
哦 她其实不是想打我
Oh, it wasn't me she was aiming at.
是想打我弟弟
She was trying for me little brother.
他可是个真正的讨厌鬼
Now he was a real pest.
第二次我九岁
Second time I was nine.
跟几个大孩子打了起来
Got in a scrap with a few older boys.
他们赢了
They won.
第三次嘛...
Third time...
嘿 你不会想知道第三次发生了什么的
Eh, you don't want to know about the third time.
可怜的鼻子
Poor nose.
不用可怜它
Don't feel sorry for him.
不等今晚过完它就会爬上你的屁股
He'll be halfway up your ass before the night's through.
桑铎・克里冈
“猎狗” 御林铁卫
欢迎之至 朋友们
Welcome, friends.
这轮算我的
This round's on me.
我想他大概不喜欢我
I don't think he likes me.
你觉得自己是条硬汉？
You think you're a hard man?
我确实是
I know it.
这里又暖和
It's warm in here.
又有漂亮女人
We've got beautiful women
还有不错的麦芽酒
and good brown ale.
足够每个人喝的
Plenty for everyone.
你却只想着
And all you want
把我们中的某个人送往冰冷地底下
is to put one of us in the cold ground
那边甚至没有女人陪伴
with no women to keep us company.
哦 那边有女人
Oh, there's women in the ground.
我亲手便送过去不少
I put some there myself.
你也送过
So have you.
你喜欢干女人
You like fucking
喝酒 唱歌
and drinking and singing.
但是杀人--
But killing--
杀人才是你的最爱
killing's the thing you love.
你就跟我一样
You're just like me.
只不过小了一号
Only smaller.
但快得多
And quicker.
嘿？
Eh?
你的主子小恶魔会想念你的
Your Lord Imp is gonna miss you.
是啊
Aye.
我想他有一天会的
I expect he will someday.
是集合钟
Here we are.
开战之前再来一杯？
One more drink before the war?
怎样？
Shall we?
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
我一直很讨厌钟声
I've always hated the bells.
响起来就没好事--
They ring for horror--
国王逝世 城市被围困
a dead king, a city under siege.
- 还有婚礼  - 是的
- A wedding. - Exactly.
波德瑞克・派恩
提利昂・兰尼斯特的侍从
他叫波德瑞克 对吗？
Podrick, is that it?
“是吗？” 装得真像
"Is that it?" Nice touch.
好像你不知道城里每个男孩的名字似的
As if you don't know the name of every boy in town.
我不明白您在暗示什么
I'm not entirely sure what you're suggesting.
我很肯定你明白我在暗示什么
I'm entirely sure you're entirely sure what I'm suggesting.
您信任他吗？
Do you trust him?
说来也怪 我很信任他
Oddly enough, I do.
很好
Good.
您要的地图
The map you asked for.
城市地下看来有二十里长的隧道
There must be 20 miles of tunnels beneath the city.
将近五十里
Closer to 50.
坦格利安家建城时不仅考虑了城防工事
The Targaryens built this city to withstand a siege
还预留了必要的逃跑路线
and to provide escape if necessary.
我不会逃跑
I'm not escaping.
听起来有点奇怪 但我是这艘船的船长
Strange as it sounds, I'm the captain of the ship.
船在人在  船亡人亡
And if the ship goes down, I go with her.
的确是豪言壮语
That is good to hear.
不过当船尚未沉没时
Though I'm sure many captains say the same
很多船长都夸下过这样的海口
while their ship is afloat.
您看上去作好了打架的准备 大人
You look well suited for battle, My Lord.
不 我才没有
Well, I'm not.
为了我们彼此 我希望您是错的
For all our sakes, I hope you are wrong.
小小鸟告诉我 史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩
My little birds tell me that Stannis Baratheon
和一位亚夏红袍女祭司鬼混在一起
has taken up with a Red Priestess from Asshai.
那又如何？
What of it?
您不相信古老的力量 大人？
You don't believe in the old powers, My Lord?
血魔法 诅咒 易形者 ―― 你相信否？
Blood spells, curses, shape-shifting-- what do you think?
我猜您笃信眼见为实
I think you believe in what you see
也相信您信任的人看见的事
and in what those you trust have seen.
您大概不会完全信任我
You probably don't entirely trust me.
嗯 别把它当成私人恩怨
Mm, don't take it personally.
其实我连我自己都不敢完全相信
I don't entirely trust myself.
但我确实看过一些事情
And yet I have seen things
听过一些事情
and heard things--
那些您不曾见闻 我也宁愿自己未曾见闻的事情
things you have not, things I wish I had not.
我好像没告诉过您我是怎么被阉割的
I don't believe I've ever told you how I was cut.
是的 你应该没说过
No, I don't believe you have.
某天我会告诉您的
One day I will.
黑暗的魔法为史坦尼斯大人带来了军队
The dark arts have provided Lord Stannis with his armies
为他铺好抵达君临城门的道路
and paved his path to our door.
侍奉此等力量的人倘若坐上铁王座
For a man in service to such powers to sit on the Iron Throne,
没有比这更可怕的事了
I can think of nothing worse.
今夜
And tonight,
我相信您是唯一能阻止他的人
I believe you are the only man who can stop him.
他们在欢迎新王
They're welcoming the new king.
我从未听说鸣钟意味投降
I've never known bells to mean surrender.
他们想奏音乐？那就合奏个痛快
They want to play music with us? Let's play.
- 击鼓 -击鼓！
- Drums. - Drums!
记住  等船――
Remember, wait till the shit--
史坦尼斯的船已经进了海湾
The ships are in the bay.
放他们深入 别让他们――
They must be far enough in so they won't be--
我懂什么是“深入”
I know what "in" means.
- 知道怎么使这家伙吗？	- 我砍过树
-Do you know how to use that? - I chopped wood once.
不 我是见过我老哥砍树
No, I watched my brother chopping wood.
我见过你用盾牌杀人
I saw you kill a man with a shield.
拿斧子的你勇不可挡
You'll be unstoppable with an axe.
- 别被杀了 - 你也一样 朋友
- Don't get killed. - Nor you, my friend.
- 噢 我们现在是朋友了？	- 当然是
- Oh, are we friends now? - Of course we are.
我付钱你效劳
Just because I pay you for your services doesn't
并不会消减我们的友谊
diminish our friendship.
反而因此升华 可不是
Enhances it, really.
噢 佣兵嘴里居然吐出“升华”这种高雅词
Oh, enhances. Fancy word for a sellsword.
和高雅的爷们儿混久了呗
Been spending time with fancy folks.
珊莎・史塔克
珊莎小姐 和 嗯 雪拉
Lady Sansa and, uh, Sheila.
雪伊
Shae.
雪伊 对
Shae, yes.
想必我姐姐邀请你跟其他贵妇人
Surely my sister has asked you to join
一起去梅葛楼了吧？
the other highborn ladies in Maegor's holdfast.
是的 大人
She has, My Lord,
但乔佛里国王召我来为他送行
but King Joffrey sent for me to see him off.
珊莎
Sansa.
乔佛里・拜拉席恩
铁王座上的王
我外甥还真浪漫啊
He's been a great romantic, my nephew.
珊莎 过来
Sansa, come here.
我会祈祷您平安归来的 大人
I will pray for your safe return, My Lord.
真的
Will you?
就像我为国王祈祷的一样
Just as I pray for the King's.
保护好自己 我的女士
Stay safe, My Lady.
你也是 我的狮子
And you, my lion.
你的国王即将出征
Your king rides forth to battle.
你要吻别他
You should see him off with a kiss.
这是我的新剑
My new blade.
我命名它为“噬心”
Hearteater I've named it.
吻它
Kiss it.
等我回来 你要再吻它
You'll kiss it again when I return
到时你会尝到我叔叔的鲜血
and taste my Uncle's blood.
您会亲自杀掉他么
Will you slay him yourself?
只要史坦尼斯蠢到向我挑战
If Stannis is fool enough to come near me.
那您会率领前锋 冲出城门喽？
So you'll be outside the gates fighting in the Vanguard?
国王可不会跟愚蠢的姑娘家
A king doesn't discuss
讨论战术
battle plans with stupid girls.
抱歉 陛下 您说得对 我很愚蠢
I'm sorry, Your Grace. You're right, I'm stupid.
您当然会率领前锋
Of course you'll be in the Vanguard.
听说我哥哥罗柏
They say my brother Robb always goes
总往战况最激烈的地方去
where the fighting is thickest.
而他还不是真正的国王呢
And he is only a pretender.
有一天会轮到你哥哥的
Your brother's turn will come.
等着在“噬心”上尝到他的鲜血吧
Then you can lick his blood off Hearteater, too.
这些男孩好多都会一去不返
Some of those boys will never come back.
乔佛里会
Joffrey will.
恶人总是能活下来
The worst ones always live.
嘘 跟我来 小姐
Shh. Come, My Lady.
蓝赛尔・兰尼斯特
凯冯・兰尼斯特之子
- 我们的舰队哪去了？ - 待会就到
- Where's our fleet? - On the way.
为何眼下不在？ 敌人已经来了
Why isn't it here now? They're coming.
猎狗 告诉首相 国王问他问题呢
Hound, tell the Hand that his King has asked him a question.
国王刚刚问你问题呢
The King has asked you a question.
蓝赛尔爵士 让猎狗告诉国王
Ser Lancel, tell the Hound to tell the king
首相忙不过来
that the Hand is extremely busy.
国王之手让我告诉你
The Hand of the King would like me to tell
再让你转告国王--
you to tell the King--
要是我让猎狗把你砍成两半
If I tell the Hound to cut you in half,
他想都不用想 直接就会动手
he'll do it without a second thought.
那我就成了“半半人”
That would make me the Quarterman.
听起来可不怎么动听
It just doesn't have the same ring to it.
把我剁了 我就没法放出信号
Cut me in half and I won't be able to give the signal.
没有信号 计划就得泡汤
No signal, no plan.
计划泡汤 史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩就会轻易拿下都城
No plan and Stannis Baratheon sacks this city,
夺走铁王座 再把你的小脑袋
takes the Iron Throne, puts your pinched
找扇城门插上去
little head atop a gate somewhere.
说不定挺喜感的
It might be quite amusing,
只不过我的脑袋也得插在那
except that my head would be up there, too.
虽说我的脑袋不怎么可爱
I've never much liked my head,
但我还不想把它丢掉
but I don't want to see it removed just yet.
怎不见敌船
Where are their ships?
看样子我们夜袭是对的 让他们措手不及了
It is wise to attack at night. We took them by surprise.
瓦里斯大人知道你三天前的早餐吃了啥
Lord Varys knows what you had for breakfast three days ago.
他们对一切都了如指掌
There are no surprises here.
听说敌营中意见不合
If it's true there is dissension in their ranks,
说不定他们的水手兵变了
maybe their sailors have mutinied.
但愿吧
Maybe.
托曼・拜拉席恩
乔佛里・拜拉席恩之弟
不知道她为什么让我到这来
I don't know why she wants me here.
她总说我多么的笨 她讨厌我
She's always saying how stupid I am. She hates me.
也许她更讨厌其他人呢
Maybe she hates you less than she hates everyone else.
我不信
I doubt it.
或者她嫉妒你呢
Maybe she's jealous of you.
我有什么好嫉妒的？
Why would she be jealous?
珊莎
Sansa.
我刚还在想 小白鸽飞到哪去了
I was wondering where our little dove had flown.
你脸色不太好 孩子
You look pale, child.
初潮还在继续？
Is your red flower still blooming?
是的
Yes.
真巧 不是么？
Fitting, isn't it?
男人在外面流血 你却在里面流
The men will bleed out there and you will bleed in here.
给珊莎小姐倒酒
Pour Lady Sansa some wine.
我不渴 陛下
I'm not thirsty, Your Grace.
那又怎样？ 又不是让你喝水
So? I didn't offer you water.
伊林・派恩
御前执法官
他在这做什么？
What's he doing here?
伊林爵士？
Ser Ilyn?
他在这保护我们
He's here to defend us.
当利斧劈开这扇门时
When the axes smash down those doors,
你就会庆幸他在这儿了
you may be glad to have him.
但我们有卫兵啊
But we have guards to defend us.
雇来的佣兵而已
Guards we have paid.
如果城池陷落 他们会争先恐后地
Should the city fall, they'll be the first ones
逃之夭夭
out of the doors.
曼登・穆尔
御林铁卫
小伙子们逮到一个马夫和两个女仆 他们偷了匹马
The lads caught a groom and two maids trying to sneak away
和几个黄金杯子 想溜出城门
with a stolen horse and some gold cups.
战斗中的第一批叛徒
The battle's first traitors.
交给伊林爵士处置
Have Ser Ilyn see to them.
把头插在枪上 挂在马厩外以儆效尤
Put their heads on spikes outside the stables as a warning.
让臣民保持忠诚的唯一办法
The only way to keep the small folk loyal
就是确保他们惧怕你胜过惧怕你的敌人
is to make certain they fear you more than they do the enemy.
如果你想成为王后的话 记住这一点
Remember that if you ever hope to become a queen.
您说他在这里是要保护我们
You said he was here to protect us.
没错
He is.
叛徒对我们所有人都是威胁
Traitors are a danger to us all.
再来一杯
More wine.
他们来了
There they are.
- 弓箭手就位 -弓箭手 就位！
- Archers to their marks. - Archers, to your marks!
弓箭手！
Archers!
拉箭上弦！
Nock your arrows!
Nock arrows!
- 稳住 - 稳住！
- Hold fast. - Hold fast!
你在想什么？ 我们得攻击才行
What are you doing? We need to attack them.
- 稳住 - 石头准备好！
- Hold fast. - Boulders ready!
稳住！
Hold fast!
怎么只有一条船 其他的船在哪？
There's only one ship. Where are the rest of them?
其他的船在哪？
Where are the rest of them?!
他们只有一条船
There's only one ship.
弓箭手 准备！
Archers, stand to!
舱下预备
Man the below!
- 上弦！ - 上弦装膛
- Nock! - Nock and set!
拉弓！
Draw!
稳住
Hold.
稳住！
Hold!
船上没人
There's no one on board.
哈林
火术士
更多石头运来了！
More rocks coming up!
稳住
Hold.
野火
Wildfire.
绕开！绕开！
Steer clear! Steer clear!
马索斯！ 趴下！
Matthos! Get down!
- 准备登陆 -陛下……
- Prepare to land. - Your Grace...
侏儒的小把戏玩得不错
The dwarf has played his little trick.
- 那可是野火―― - 这种把戏他只能玩一次
- The wildfire-- - He can only play it once.
我们离城门太远
We're too far from the gates.
野火 弓箭手
The fire, their archers--
过河会死几百人
hundreds will die.
几千人
Thousands.
跟我上 拿下都城！
Come with me and take this city!
唐托斯・霍拉德
弄臣
珊莎 过来吧 小白鸽
Sansa, come here, little dove.
太后陛下
My queen.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
祈祷
Praying.
你是个完美的女孩 对么？
You're perfect, aren't you?
祈祷
Praying.
你在祈祷什么？
What are you praying for?
祈祷诸神赐予大家慈悲
For the Gods to have mercy on us all.
噢 大家？
Oh. On all of us?
- 是的 陛下  - 连我在内？
- Yes, Your Grace. - Even me?
当然 陛下
Of course, Your Grace.
乔佛里也在内？
Even Joffrey?
- 乔佛里是我的--  - 噢 闭嘴吧 你这个小傻瓜
- Joffrey is my-- - Oh, shut up, you little fool.
祈祷诸神赐予大家慈悲
Praying to the Gods to have mercy on us all.
诸神没有慈悲 所以他们才是神
The Gods have no mercy. That's why they're Gods.
我父亲在我祈祷的时候曾这么教诲我
My father told me that when he caught me praying.
你瞧 那时我母亲刚去世
My mother just died, you see.
我还不懂得什么是死亡
I didn't really understand the concept of death,
什么是终结
the finality of it.
我以为只要非常非常虔诚地祈祷
I thought that if I prayed very, very hard,
诸神就会把母亲还给我 毕竟我才四岁
the Gods would return my mother to me. I was four.
您父亲不信仰诸神吗？
Your father doesn't believe in the Gods?
他信仰诸神 只是不大喜欢他们
He believes in them, he just doesn't like them very much.
给她来一杯
One for her.
拿去
Here.
坐下
Sit.
喝吧
Drink.
不对不对 是喝 小丫头
Not like that. Drink, girl.
我本该生为男子
I should have been born a man.
我宁可面对千百刀剑 也胜过无助地困在这里
I'd rather face 1,000 swords than be shut up inside
跟这群受惊的母鸡为伴
with this flock of frightened hens.
她们是受您保护的客人
They are your guests under your protection.
您邀请她们来的
You asked them here.
我当然要这样
It was expected of me,
将来如果你成为乔佛里的王后 你也得这么做
as it will be of you if you ever become Joffrey's queen.
若我那可恶的弟弟侥幸成功
If my wretched brother should somehow prevail,
这些母鸡就会回到她们的公鸡身边
these hens will return to their cocks
宣传我是如何勇敢地激励她们
and crow of how my courage inspired them,
振作她们的精神
lifted their spirits.
要是城堡陷落呢？
And if the city should fall?
你就希望那样 对不对？
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
红堡或许还能坚守一时
The Red Keep should hold for a time,
令我有时间登上城墙
long enough for me to go to the walls
亲自向史坦尼斯公爵请降
and yield to Lord Stannis in person.
城外若是换做别人
If it were anyone else outside those gates,
我还能试试去哄他
I might have hoped for a private audience.
但这是史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩
But this is Stannis Baratheon.
我还不如去哄他的马
I'd have a better chance of seducing his horse.
我吓到你了 小白鸽？
Have I shocked you, little dove?
眼泪并非女人唯一的武器
Tears aren't a woman's only weapon.
最好的那件在你两腿之间
The best one's between your legs.
要学会如何用它 喝啊
Learn how to use it. Drink.
你知道当一座城市陷落时
Do you have any notion of what happens
会发生什么事吗？
when a city is sacked?
不 你不知道 对吧？
No, you wouldn't, would you?
如果都城沦陷 这些贵妇人们
If the city falls, these fine women
恐怕都得忍受一点强暴
should be in for a bit of a rape.
到第二天早上 她们中的一半人
Half of them will have bastards
肚子里都会怀上野种
in their bellies come the morning.
到时候你就会为你的小红花高兴了
You'll be glad of your red flower then.
当男人血气上涌时
When a man's blood is up,
所有长乳头的对他来说都很美妙
anything with tits looks good.
像你这么个尤物
A precious thing like you
简直没法、没法抗拒
will look very, very good.
就像是一块
A slice of cake
送上门的甜美蛋糕
just waiting to be eaten.
加把劲！
More pressure!
- 划啊！划啊！ - 就这样 弟兄们！
- Pull! Pull! - That's it, men!
划啊！划啊！
Pull! Pull!
就这样！稳住！
That's it! Steady!
真是个难缠的家伙――史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩
He's a serious man-- Stannis Baratheon.
他们来了 要上岸了
They're coming. They're coming ashore.
给他们来场火雨
Rain fire on them.
弓箭手！
Archers!
他们人太多了
There are too many.
猎狗 为挣扎上岸的拜拉席恩军队
Hound, form a welcome party for any Baratheon troop
组织一场欢迎晚宴
that manages to touch solid ground.
波德 立刻跑去国王大门
Pod, run to the King's gate.
把那里所有的守卫都带过来
Bring any men guarding it here now.
是 大人
Yes, My Lord.
跟我上 史坦尼斯送鲜肉来了
Let's go. Stannis is sending us fresh meat.
你也给我上
You, too.
如果有一根该死的火箭靠近了我
Any of these flaming fucking arrows come near me,
我就用你的肠子勒死你
I'll strangle you with your own guts.
划啊 划啊！上啊！
Pull, pull! Go!
搭箭！
Nock!
拉弓！
Draw!
- 拉弓！ - 拉弓！
- Draw! - Draw!
干翻兰尼斯特！
Kill the Lannisters!
放！
Loose!
成列！
Form the line!
史坦尼斯万岁！
Stannis!
- 拉弓！ - 拉弓！
- Draw! - Draw!
- 放！ - 放！
- Loose! - Loose!
他们攻不破城墙！
They cannot breach the wall!
去烂泥门！立刻！
The mud gate, go now!
第一小队和第二小队 去城门！去烂泥门！
First and second squads, to the gate! To the mud gate!
谁要是死的时候还留着把干净的剑
Any man dies with a clean sword,
我就操烂谁的尸体
I'll rape his fucking corpse.
小时候
When we were young, Jaime and I,
詹姆和我长得太像
we looked so much alike.
甚至连我们的父亲也常分不清
Even our father couldn't tell us apart.
我永远无法理解为何彼此会受到迥异的对待
I could never understand why they treated us differently.
詹姆练习长剑、枪矛和钉头锤
Jaime was taught to fight with sword and lance and mace,
我却练习微笑
and I was taught to smile
唱歌和讨人欢喜
and sing and please.
他成了凯岩城的继承人
He was heir to Casterly Rock
我则像马一样被卖给陌生人
and I was sold to some stranger like a horse
新主人想骑就骑
to be ridden whenever he desired.
您是劳勃的王后
You were Robert's queen.
而你将成为乔佛里的王后 好好享受吧
And you will be Joffrey's. Enjoy.
我想我不认识这个人
I don't think I know this one.
很漂亮
Pretty.
这是我见过最糟糕的屈膝礼
That's the worst curtsy I've ever seen.
实际上 这并不难 我四岁时就学会了
Here, it's not difficult. I mastered it when I was four.
挺直你的背 然后屈膝
Straighten your back and bend.
好多了 你学得挺快
Better. You learn fast.
你当珊莎小姐的侍女多久了？
How long have you been in Lady Sansa's service?
数周 陛下
A few weeks, Your Grace.
你离开罗拉斯多久了？
When did you leave Lorath?
我有过一个罗拉斯女仆
I had a Lorathi handmaiden once.
但她是个贵族小姐
But she was a nobleman's daughter.
你不是
You're not.
你什么时候来维斯特洛的？
When did you come to Westeros?
十年前 陛下
10 years ago, Your Grace.
十年来 你从一介罗拉斯平民
From Lorathi commoner to the Red Keep
混到进红堡当差 却还没学会屈膝礼
in 10 years, all without learning how to curtsy.
我想这是个非常有趣的故事
I imagine that's a very interesting story.
你叫什么？
What's your name?
雪伊 陛下
Shae, Your Grace.
给我们讲讲故事吧 雪伊
Tell us a story, Shae.
我十三岁时――
When I was 13, I--
陛下！
Your Grace!
战况如何？
What news?
小恶魔把整条河点着了
The Imp has set the river afire.
上百条船在燃烧 或许更多
Hundreds of ships are burning, maybe more.
史坦尼斯的舰队毁了 可……
Stannis's fleet destroyed, but...
可―可他的军队
But-- but his troops
在城外登陆了
have landed outside the city walls.
乔佛里在哪？
Where is Joffrey?
跟提利昂大人一起在城墙上
On the battlements with Lord Tyrion.
立刻把他带回来
Bring him back inside at once.
- 可是 陛下――  - 什么？
- But, Your Grace-- - What?
国王留在前线会极大地鼓舞士气
The King's presence is good for morale.
立刻带他回房
Bring him back to his chambers now.
- 不是这里？ - 跟妇女孩子们一起？
- Not here? - With the women and children?
你希望他的余生一直被嘲笑为懦夫吗？
Do you want him to be mocked as a coward for the rest of his life?
- 不  可我―― - 快去！
- No, but I-- - Now!
之前跟你说伊林・派恩爵士的时候 我撒了谎
When I told you about Ser Ilyn earlier, I lied.
想不想听实话？
Do you want to hear the truth?
想不想知道我叫他来的真正原因？
You want to know why he's really here?
他为我们而来
He's here for us.
史坦尼斯也许能攻进都城 夺取王位
Stannis may take the city, he may take the throne,
但他绝不可能生擒我们
but he will not take us alive.
啊！救命！
Ah! Help me!
快跑！
We'd better run!
撤退！
Fall back!
把梯子架起来！
Get the ladders up!
快点 杂种！快点！
Faster, you bastards! Faster!
给我上 宰了那些人渣！
Come on, kill the scum!
给我拿点喝的
Someone bring me a drink.
操你妈的水 拿酒来
Fuck the water. Bring me wine.
要我给你来杯冰牛奶么？
Can I get you some iced milk
外加一碗可口的果莓？
and a nice bowl of raspberries, too?
吃屎吧 侏儒
Eat shit, dwarf.
你该待在城墙外面杀敌才对
You're on the wrong side of the wall.
我损失了一半人手
I lost half my men.
黑水河在燃烧
The Blackwater's on fire.
狗 我命令你回到那边继续战斗
Dog, I command you to go back out there and fight.
你是御林铁卫 克里冈
You're Kingsguard, Clegane.
你必须打退他们 否则他们就要拿下这座城――
You must beat them back or they're going to take this city--
你国王的都城
your king's city.
操你妈的御林铁卫
Fuck the Kingsguard.
操你妈的都城
Fuck the city.
操你妈的国王
Fuck the King.
放！
Loose!
身子藏到里面！
Put your backs into it!
好 举起来！
All right, get up!
放！
Loose!
准备！
Clear!
向前！
Forward!
放！
Loose!
云梯上前！
Forward ladders!
他们要上城墙了！
They're coming up the wall!
北墙弓箭手准备！
Archers on the north wall!
撞！
-
- Heave!
撞！
陛下
Your Grace,
太后命我带您返回红堡
the queen has sent me to bring you back to the Red Keep.
如果你都不保卫自己的都城 他们又为什么要拼命？
If you won't defend your own city, why should they?
你想让我怎么做？
What would you have me do?
留下来
Lead.
下到战场 统率你的士兵
Get down there and lead your people
打败嗜血的入侵者
against the invaders who want to kill them.
我母亲到底是怎么说的？
What did my mother say exactly?
她是否有要事与我商讨？
Did she have urgent business with me?
她没有详说 陛下
She did not say, Your Grace.
所有人到城垛顶住！
All men to the battlements!
柏洛斯爵士  曼登爵士
Ser Boros, Ser Mandon,
和我舅舅呆在一起  在战场上
stay with my Uncle and represent the king
代表国王
on the field on battle.
弓箭手 稳住阵线
Archers, hold your line
否则我宰了你们
or I'll kill you myself.
稳住阵脚！
Stand fast!
不！
No!
起来 你这蠢货
Get up, you fool.
我们需要更多的箭
We need more arrows!
国王在哪儿？
Where is the king?
- 他为什么不和我们在一起？ - 我们这是为谁而战？
- Why isn't he with us? - Who are we fighting for?
谁来领军？
Who leads us?
我来带领突击
I'll lead the attack.
我来带领突击！
I'll lead the attack!
- 什么？ - 你说什么？
- Yes? - What are you talking about?
波德 我的头盔
Pod, my helmet.
曼登爵士 由你执掌国王的旗帜
Ser Mandon, you will bear the King's banner.
士兵整队
Men, form up.
士兵――
Men--
- 士兵们！  -算了吧
- men! - Come on.
他们说我是个半人
They say I'm half a man.
那你们这些“完人”比我多出了什么？
But what does that make the lot of you?
城门是唯一的出路
The only way out is through the gates.
却被他们堵住了
And they're at the gates.
还有一条路 我带你们走
There's another way out. I'm going to show you.
从背后偷袭 狠操他们的屁眼
We'll come out behind them and fuck them in their asses.
撞！
Heave!
你们不是为国王
Don't fight for your king
也不是为王国而战
and don't fight for his kingdoms.
不为头衔 不为荣誉
Don't fight for honor. Don't fight for glory.
也不为金银珠宝 这些统统都是屁话
Don't fight for riches, because you won't get any.
史坦尼斯要洗劫你们的城市
This is your city Stannis means to sack.
要撞开你们的城门
That's your gate he's ramming.
如果他得逞 被烧的将是你们的房子
If he gets in, it will be your houses he burns,
被抢的将是你们的金子
your gold he steals,
被操的将是你们的女人
your women he will rape.
撞！ 撞！
Heave! Heave!
撞城的都是些勇士
Those are brave me knocking at our door.
让我们杀光他们！
Let's go kill them.
我们输定了 陛下
The battle is lost, Your Grace.
史坦尼斯兵临城下
Stannis's troops are at the gates.
金袍子却眼睁睁看着国王溜走
When the Gold Cloaks saw the king leaving,
军心顿时涣散
they lost all heart.
我儿子在哪里？
Where is my son?
我希望能护送他回战场
I want to escort him back to the battle.
你的想法关我什么事？
Why do I care what you want?
- 给我―― - 听我说 - 啊！
- Bring me-- - Now listen to me-- ah!
别害怕 太后升起了吊桥
Don't be afraid. The queen has raised the drawbridge.
这里是全城最安全的地方
This is the safest place we can be.
乔佛里毫发无伤 他正在英勇奋战
Joffrey's not hurt. He's fighting bravely.
骑士们团结在他身后
His knights have rallied behind him.
他们会拯救这个城市
They will save the city.
让我们唱首圣歌吧？
Shall we sing a hymn?
温柔的圣母
Gentle mother
慈悲的源泉
font of mercy
保佑您的儿子穿越鏖战
save our sons from war, we pray
- 温柔的圣母 - 你得快走
- gentle--  - You must go.
回房间去 插好门闩
Run to your chamber and bar your door.
史坦尼斯不会伤害你 这个人会
Stannis won't hurt you. This one will.
跟我一起走
Come with me.
我还要和一个人道别
I need to say goodbye to someone.
太后说他们会强奸每一个女人
The queen said they'd rape everyone.
没人能强奸我
No one is raping me.
走吧 快
Go. Run.
保佑您的儿子穿越鏖战
save our sons from war, we pray.
小淑女也开始恐慌了
The lady is starting to panic.
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
我不会久留
Not here for long.
- 我要离开 - 去哪儿？
- I'm going. - Where?
随便哪里 只要没有火焰
Someplace that isn't burning.
也许是北方
North, might be.
可以是北方
Could be.
国王怎么办？
What about the king?
他一个人也可以死
He can die just fine on his own.
我可以带上你
I can take you with me.
带你去临冬城
Take you to Winterfell.
保你一路平安
I'll keep you safe.
你想回家吗？
Do you want to go home?
我留在这里很安全
I'll be safe here.
史坦尼斯不会伤害我
Stannis won't hurt me.
看着我
Look at me.
史坦尼斯是个凶手
Stannis is a killer.
就像兰尼斯特
The Lannisters are killers.
就像你父亲
Your father was a killer.
就像你哥哥一样
Your brother is a killer.
总有一天 你的儿子也会变成凶手
Your sons will be killers someday.
世界属于这帮凶手
The world is built by killers.
所以你最好习惯看着他们
So you'd better get used to looking at them.
你不会伤害我
You won't hurt me.
对 小小鸟 我不会伤害你
No, little bird, I won't hurt you.
撞！ 撞！
Heave! Heave!
快啊 杂种们！上梯！
Come on, you bastards! Get up those ladders!
啊！
Ah!
进攻！
Attack!
掀翻它！
Roll it over!
半人万岁！半人万岁！
Halfman! Halfman! Halfman! Halfman!
噢 操蛋
Oh, fuck me.
嘘
Shh.
别动 小甜心
Be calm, my sweet.
外面还在打
They're still fighting.
没人会伤害你的
No one's going to hurt you.
我来给你讲个故事
I'll tell you a story.
你听过狮子妈妈和小狮子的故事吗？
You know the one about the mother lion and her little cub?
- 他们住在树林里 - 是御林
- They lived in the woods. - The Kingswood.
对 亲爱的
Yes, my love.
御林里住着狮子妈妈和她的小狮子
In the Kingswood there lived a mother and her cub.
她非常爱他
She loved him very much.
但林子里有其他动物
But there were other things that lived in the woods.
- 坏动物 - 比如说？
- Evil things. - Like what?
比如雄鹿
Like stags.
雄鹿才不坏呢
Stags aren't evil.
它们只吃草
They only eat grass.
还有狼
And wolves.
大人
My Lord.
夜里 小狮子总能听到狼的嗥叫
He could hear them howling in the night.
他非常害怕
The little cub was frightened.
于是狮子妈妈说:“好孩子 你是狮子
His mother said, "You are a lion, my son.
你不能害怕
You mustn't be afraid.
总有一天 所有的野兽都会臣服于你
For one day all the beasts will bow to you.
尊你为王
You will be king.
雄鹿和狼会在你面前屈膝
All the stags will bow.all the wolves will bow.
还有北边的熊与南边的狐狸
The bears in the north and the foxes of the south,
天上的飞鸟 水里的海怪
all the birds in the sky and the beasts in the sea--
小狮子 他们都会伏在你脚下……
they will all come to you, little lion...
把王冠放在你头顶”
to rest a crown upon your head."
小狮子说
And the cub said,
“我会不会像我父亲那样强壮凶猛？”
"Will I be strong and fierce like my father?"
“当然了” 狮子妈妈说
"Yes," said his mother.
“你会强壮凶猛 和你父亲一模一样”
"You will be strong and fierce just like your father."
亲爱的 我会保护你
I will keep you safe, my love.
我向你保证
I promise you.
撤回船上！
Back to the boats!
留下来战斗！
Stand and fight!
留下来战斗！该死的！
Stand and fight, damn you!
不！
No!
洛拉斯・提利尔
“百花骑士”
泰温・兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 西境守护
父亲
Father.
战斗结束了 我们大获全胜
The battle is over. We have won.
衣柜字幕组出品
“汝何德何能？” 爵爷傲然宣称
"And who are you," the proud lord said
维斯特洛名曲《卡斯特梅的雨季》：高傲的塔贝克家与卡斯特梅家不服兰尼斯特家的统治，于是泰温公爵亲自带军把这两家满门抄斩，城堡摧毁，然后找歌手作歌一曲――《卡斯特梅的雨季》。
“须令吾躬首称臣？
"that I must bow so low?
颜色有别 威力不逊
only a cat of a different coat
各显神通分个高低
that's all the truth I know
红狮子斗黄狮子
in a coat of gold or a coat of red
爪牙锋利不留情
a lion still has claws
出手致命招招狠
and mine are long and sharp, My Lord
汝子莫忘记 汝子莫忘记”
as long and sharp as yours"
噢 他这样说 他这样说
and so he spoke, and so he spoke
卡斯特梅的爵爷他这样说
that Lord of Castamere
然而今天 每逢雨季
but now the rains weep o'ver his hall
雨水在大厅哭泣 内里却无人影
with no one there to hear
然而今天 每逢雨季
yes, now the rains weep o'er his hall
雨水在大厅哭泣 内里却无魂灵
and not a soul to hear.